<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Golang on Long Wang </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/categories/golang/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 02:17:49 EDT</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv</title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/pages/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 02:17:49 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/pages/cv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 - present: Ph. D. in Mechanical Engineering, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2010 - 2012: M. Sc. in Mechanical Engineering, Columbia University, New York, NY, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2006 - 2010: B. Sc. in Mechanical Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-interests:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design, control &amp;amp; telemanipulation of continuum robots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calibration and modeling of continuum robots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robot hybrid force motion control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;projects:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligent Flexible Robots for Safe Manipulation of Anatomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calibration of continuous medical robots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hybrid force motion control of the Puma robot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telemanipulation control using virtual fixture of the Puma robot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peer-reviewed-journal-papers:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Peer Reviewed Journal Papers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simaan, N., Bajo, A., Reiter, A., &lt;strong&gt;Long, W.&lt;/strong&gt;, Allen, P. &amp;amp; Fowler, D. (2013). Lessons learned using the insertable robotic effector platform (IREP) for single port access surgery. Journal of Robotic Surgery.Special Issue: Hamlyn Symposium 2012]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groom, K., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Simaan, N. &amp;amp; Netterville, J. (2015). Robot- Assisted Trans-nasal Laryngoplasty in Cadaveric Models: Quantifying Forces and Identifying Challenges. The Laryngoscope, 125(5), 166-168.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peer-reviewed-conference-papers:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Peer Reviewed Conference Papers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Chen, Z., Chalasani, P., Pile, J., Kazanzides, P., Talor, R. H., Simaan, N., ”Updating Virtual Fixtures From Exploration Data in Force-controlled Model-based Telemanipulation,” International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference (ASME IDETC), Charlotte, NC, USA, 2016 (accepted).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Simaan, N (2014). Investigation of Error Propagation in Multi-Backbone Continuum Robots. In Advances in Robot Kinematics, pages 385-394. Springer International Publishing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bajo, A., Goldman, R. E., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Fowler, D. &amp;amp; Simaan, N (2012). Integration and Preliminary Evaluation of an Insertable Robotic Effectors Platform for Single Port Access Surgery. In International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA’2012), pages 3381-3387. [&lt;strong&gt;finalist best medical robotics paper&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roy, R., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Simaan, N (2015). Investigation of Effects of Dynamics on Intrinsic Wrench Sensing in Continuum Robots. In International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA’2016), [&lt;strong&gt;finalist best medical robotics paper&lt;/strong&gt;].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chalasani, P., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Roy, R., Simaan, N. &amp;amp; Taylor, R. H (2016). Concurrent Nonparametric Estimation of Organ Geometry and Tissue Stiffness Using Continuous Adaptive Palpation. InInternational Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA’2016), in press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ayvali, E., Srivatsan, A., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Roy, R., Simaan, N. &amp;amp; Choset, H (2016). Using Bayesian Optimization to Guide Probing of a Flexible Environment for Simultaneous Registration and Stiffness Mapping. In International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA’2016), in press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Srinivasan, A., Ayvali, E., &lt;strong&gt;Wang, L.&lt;/strong&gt;, Roy, R., Simaan, N. &amp;amp; Choset, H (2016). Complementary model update: A method for simultaneous registration and stiffness mapping in flexible environments. In International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA’2016), in press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Wang&lt;/strong&gt;, Joseph DelPreto, Sam Bhattacharyya, Jonathan Weisz, and Peter K. Allen, “A highly-underactuated robotic hand with force and joint angle sensors”, IEEE/RSJ Inter. Conf. IROS 2011, San Francisco, California, USA, pp 1380 - 1385, 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Wang&lt;/strong&gt;, Wenzeng Zhang, Yuming Ye, et al. “The indirect style under-actuated robotic finger with tendon-slider mechanisms,” in Proc. IEEE Inter. Conf. Robio 2009, Guilin, China, pp 1790 - 1795, 2009.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wenzeng Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;Long Wang&lt;/strong&gt;, Li Hao, et al. “An indirect style linkage under-actuated humanoid robot hand,” 2010 IEEE Informatics in Control, Automation and Robotics (CAR), Wuhan, China, pp 421 - 424, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wenzeng Zhang, Jie Sun, Deyang Zhao, &lt;strong&gt;Long Wang&lt;/strong&gt;, “A Novel Coupled and Self-adaptive Under-actuated Multi-fingered Hand with Gear-rack-slider Mechanism,” in Proc. IEEE Inter. Conf. 9th International Conference on Frontiers of Design and Manufacturing Science, Changsha, China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities:7e6115c4d209379befeb3847e8c4905b&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Former leader of Tsinghua University Concert Band (2007-2009).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsinghua University outstanding student leaders (2006).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tsinghua University Arts scholarship (2008).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Hand Project</title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/robotic_hand_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 03:23:52 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/robotic_hand_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotic hand projects led my way to this field. They were my initial interests and I am still interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my robitics journey from junior year when I was in Tsinghua University, Beijing.
One day I saw this cool robotic hand project in Dr. Wenzeng Zhang&amp;rsquo;s lab and asked him if I could work with him.
He said yes, and then for the next two years, I worked with him and learned a lot from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After undergraduate, I decided to continue to graduate study. I had the honor to work with Dr. Peter Allen in his Robotics Lab at Columbia University.
I spent almost two years there and it was exciting and very fun because we got to build a robotics hand from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wanglong06.github.io/columbia_hand.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Columbia Hand&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/uBmQz1yC5rs&#34; title=&#34;Video Title&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.youtube.com/vi/uBmQz1yC5rs/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMAGE ALT TEXT&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Force-controlled Exploration and Telemanipulation</title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/force_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:42:04 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/force_control/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuum Robots used in Surgical Applications </title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/continuum_robots_surgical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:31:33 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/continuum_robots_surgical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuum robots are sometimes also called snake-like robots. This topic becomes my main research interest for the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and Trumpet</title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/me_and_trumpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 03:38:19 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/me_and_trumpet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love listening to trumpet pieces and playing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to play trumpet when I was young but unfortunately never able to play so well. I was playing in middle school, high school and colledge and now I am playing in community concert band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wanglong06.github.io/long_wang_2013a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Example image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and Photography</title>
      <link>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/me_and_photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 03:44:33 EDT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wanglong06.github.io/post/me_and_photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is new for me but I enjoy learning and exploring.
It is fun to capture beautiful scenery and landscape from different places when traveling.
But I like it more to capture people, to seize the interesting moments in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
